Dick Russell Papers MS277
Tufts Archival Research Center
Dick Russell Papers
circa 1965 -- 2000
Tufts Archival Research Center
Rusell, Dick
MS277
24 Linear Feet 24 record cartons
This collection contains journalist Dick Russells's subject files, including research material and clippings related to his coverage of environmental issues, including the work of Lois Gibbs and the Love Canal crisis.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of interview transcripts, correspondence, and notes compiled during the course of Dick Russell's reporting career. It includes an array of clippings from various publications that detail environmental issues in the 1970s, 1980s, and 1990s. Topics include environmental disasters, hazardous waste, pollution, nuclear power, state government environmental policies, military, acid rain, animal rights, renewable energy, and environmental activist groups. Activist groups mentioned in these notes, interviews, and clippings include EarthFirst!, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), Greenpeace, Natural Resources Defense Council (NRDC), and other bioregional groups. There are also news clippings and interview notes relating to Lois Gibbs, dioxin, and the Love Canal crisis.
Biographical / Historical
Dick Russell (1947 - ) is a journalist and writer whose career has primarily focused on environmental issues.
Richard B. Russell, also known as Dick, was born on August 19, 1947, in Minneapolis, Minnesota. He received his bachelor's degree from the University of Kansas in 1969, and worked as a sports and feature writer with the Topeka Capital-Journal in Kansas (1965 to 1972); Sports Illustrated (1969-1970); and TV Guide (1977 to 1979). In 1980 he began his career as a freelance journalist, writing for such publications as The Nation, Parenting, and Family Health, and OnEarth (formerly Amicus Journal, for which he was also a contributing editor for 18 years). He has been a guest on television and radio programs including the NBC Nightly News and the Joan Rivers Show.
Russell has written twelve books, two of which advocate for marine conservation: "Eye of the Whale: Epic Passage from Baja to Siberia," Simon & Schuster (New York, NY), 2001 and "Striper Wars: An American Fish Story," Island Press/Shearwater Books (Washington, DC), 2005. His 2017 work, Horsemen of the "Apocalypse: The Men Who Are Destroying Life On Earth – and What It Means For Our Children," Simon & Schuster (New York, NY), covers the political landscape of climate change. His travels across Europe and Africa are the subject of a 2017 documentary, "Hitchhiking to the Edge of Sanity," which premiered at the Kansas City Film Festival in 2016.
Dick Russell won the Golden Swordfish Award from the National Coalition for Marine Conservation in 1984 and the Citizen's Chevron Conservation Award in 1988 for exceptional service to the cause of conservation. "Eye of the Whale" won Best Book of the Year designations from both the Los Angeles Times and Washington Post in 2001.
Dick Russell is married to Alice Faber with one child, Franklin D. Russell. He divides his time between Los Angles and Boston.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in received order.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Dick Russell, 2018, accession MS-2019-017.
Climatic changes; Environmental policy.; Environmental health.; Environmental history; Gibbs, Lois
- Incineration, 1992 -- 1994; MS277.000001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
- Business and environmental correspondence, circa 1990s; MS277.000002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Gulf War / Ecology, circa 1989 -- 1991; MS277.000003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Pollution trading / Market environmentalism, 1993 -- 1994; MS277.000004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Law / (Environmental) / Justice, 1992 -- 1994; MS277.000005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Energy oil pipelines / Power lines / Dams / Electromagnetic, 1993; MS277.000006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Transportation and environment (rail, etc.), 1993 -- 1994; MS277.000007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Ecosystems (damage to / destruction of) / Biosphere, 1993 -- 1994; MS277.000008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Biodiversity, 1993 September -- 1993 November; MS277.000009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Environment: general (environmentalism), 1992 -- 1994; MS277.000010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bioregionalism, 1992 -- 1994; MS277.000011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Trudy Coxe / Amicus story, 1995 -- 1997; MS277.000012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Harvard power plant piece, 1980 -- 1984; MS277.000013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Drinking water - Ground water and aquifer, circa 1976 -- 1988; MS277.000014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 14)
- LA Air clips, 1985 -- 1989; MS277.000015; 2 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- California - Environment (miscellaneous), 1986 -- 1987; MS277.000016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Tom Hayden, 1986 -- 1988; MS277.000017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Michael Belliveau / Citizens for a Better Environment (CBE), 1982 -- 1988; MS277.000018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Proposition 65 clips related issues, 1986 -- 1988; MS277.000019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Proposition 65 interviews and contacts and Nation P.C., 1986 -- 1988; MS277.000020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- California - Toxics (general), circa 1986 -- 1988; MS277.000021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Water quality - Los Angeles, California, national, circa 1975 -- 1988; MS277.000022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Air pollution - general, circa 1976 -- 1989; MS277.000023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Air quality (California primarily) interviews, 1986 -- 1988; MS277.000024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Acid rain clippings by date, circa 1982 -- 1988; MS277.000025; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- International environment, circa 1988 -- 1991; MS277.000026; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- African and third-world dumping and pollution, 1988 -- 1991; MS277.000027; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Envirotech, green consumption, green farming, 1993 -- 1994; MS277.000028; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Environmental Protections Agency (EPA), 1982 -- 1988; MS277.000029; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- EPA story, 1987 -- 1988; MS277.000030; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Garbage - Landfills / Incineration, circa 1985 -- 1989; MS277.000031; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Waste / Recycling, 1987 -- 1989; MS277.000032; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Health and worker safety, 1987 -- 1988; MS277.000033; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Indoor pollution (lead, radon, asbestos etc.), 1981 -- 1988; MS277.000034; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Toxics - general, 1988 -- 1989; MS277.000035; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Toxics - hazardous waste general and chemicals, circa 1976 -- 1988; MS277.000036; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Dow Chemical, 1947, 1964, 1983 -- 1988; MS277.000037; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Hazardous waste incineration, 1987 -- 1988; MS277.000038; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Hydrogen fluoride / Racon etc., 1987 -- 1989; MS277.000039; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Trash crisis recycling (incineration etc.), 1985 -- 1988; MS277.000040; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Greenpeace - Anti-pollution campaigns, 1983 - - 1988; MS277.000041; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Approaches to source reduction of hazardous waste, 1986; MS277.000042; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Chemical explosions, 1988 May -- 1988 August; MS277.000043; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Chemical weapons, 1981 -- 1987; MS277.000044; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Toxics conference 1988, 1987 -- 1988; MS277.000045; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Environmental task force bulletins, 1983 -- 1986; MS277.000046; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Dioxin, circa 1983 -- 1990; MS277.000047; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Acid rain B - booklets etc. notes, circa 1981 -- 1983; MS277.000048; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Environmental - General - World environmental problems, circa 1982 -- 1988; MS277.000049; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 12)
- F - G old, circa 1987 -- 1988; MS277.000050; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Environment - New England, circa 1982 -- 1988; MS277.000051; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Environmental organizations, circa 1982 -- 1988; MS277.000052; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Law and environment, 1987 -- 1988; MS277.000053; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Natural Resources Defense Council (NRDC), 1985 -- 1988; MS277.000054; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Presidential candidates and the environment 1988, 1985 -- 1988; MS277.000055; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Our letters and replies environment, 1988 March -- 1988 September; MS277.000056; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- General articles - environmental, 1984 -- 1988; MS277.000057; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- "Environment Future" groups and individual research, 1980 -- 1988; MS277.000058; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Environmental reports, 1986 -- 1987; MS277.000059; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Rick Sutherland / Sierra Club legal defense fund, 1980 -- 1986; MS277.000060; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 9)
- David Roe and Tom Graff environmental defense fund, 1987; MS277.000061; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 10)
- California League of Conservation Voters Lucy Blake, 1982 -- 1988; MS277.000062; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 11)
- David Brower / Earth Island institute, 1986 -- 1989; MS277.000063; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Max Linn / John Muir Institute for Environmental Studies, 1978 -- 1987; MS277.000064; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Saul Bloom / Arc, circa 1982; MS277.000065; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Center for Investigative Reporting / David Weir, 1985 -- 1987; MS277.000066; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Huey Johnson / New Renaissance Center, 1981 -- 1987; MS277.000067; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Denis Hayes, 1978 -- 1987; MS277.000068; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Will and Jean Siri, 1987 January -- 1987 August; MS277.000069; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 18)
- League of Conservation Voters, 1984 -- 1988; MS277.000070; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 19)
- California Planning and Conservation League / Gerald Meral, 1986 -- 1987; MS277.000071; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Sierra Club (Mike McCloskey et al), 1986 -- 1987; MS277.000072; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Greenpeace story - update, 1986; MS277.000073; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Greenpeace - general (publications etc.), 1982 -- 1988; MS277.000074; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Greenpeace - Amicus journal story, interviews, 1983 -- 1985; MS277.000075; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Greenpeace clippings November - December 1985, 1982 -- 1986; MS277.000076; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Dave Foreman / Earth First, circa 1983 -- 1988; MS277.000077; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Green Conference July 1987, 1984 -- 1987; MS277.000078; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Colorado environment, 1986 -- 1988; MS277.000079; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Animal rights, 1985 -- 1987; MS277.000080; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Wildlife and hunting, 1976 -- 1988; MS277.000081; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Jerry Mander / Public media center, 1979 -- 1988; MS277.000082; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Montana wilderness fight, 1992 -- 1993; MS277.000083; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Land development, rivers, wetlands, 1981 -- 1988; MS277.000084; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Forests - Redwoods, national forest service, etc., 1986 -- 1988; MS277.000085; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Alan Davis / Conservatree Paper Co., 1987 January; MS277.000086; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Direct action story, 1987 January -- 1987 November; MS277.000087; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Green Party conference - July 1987 notes, 1987 July -- 1987 August; MS277.000088; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Jerry Gwathney / Green Letter, 1987 January -- 1987 August; MS277.000089; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Greens / Charlene Spretnak / Danny Moses, 1987 February -- 1987 November; MS277.000090; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Green movement, 1987 March -- 1987 November; MS277.000091; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Deep ecology - Gary Snyder, 1987 February; MS277.000092; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Kelly Kindscher, 1987 April -- 1987 August; MS277.000093; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Bioregional groups (materials received from), 1986 -- 1987; MS277.000094; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Thomas Berry, 1987 September 14 -- 1987 September 18; MS277.000095; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Jim Swan, 1987 February 17; MS277.000096; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 20)
- John Todd, 1989 October 30; MS277.000097; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Ernest Callenbach, 1987 February; MS277.000098; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Deep ecology and George Sessions, 1986 January -- 1987 February; MS277.000099; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Deep ecology story, 1987 -- 1988; MS277.000100; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Peter Berg bioregionalism, 1986 -- 1987; MS277.000101; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Rainforest, circa 1988 -- 1991; MS277.000102; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Soviet Union (environment etc.), circa 1987 -- 1991; MS277.000103; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Japan / Environment, circa 1988 -- 1991; MS277.000104; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Air quality (Los Angeles) 1990-1991, circa 1989 -- 1991; MS277.000105; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Ed Begley Jr., 1995 -- 1996; MS277.000106; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Healthy Interiors - East-West Journal, 1989 -- 1993; MS277.000107; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Amicus / Sustainable President's Council, circa 1993 -- 1994; MS277.000108; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Toxics Coordinating Project assignment, 1987 -- 1989; MS277.000109; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Waste dumps - Indian lands (general), 1990 -- 1991; MS277.000110; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Pine Ridge water pipeline and zeolite mining, 1978 -- 1992; MS277.000111; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Pine Ridge Phil Stevens, 1987 -- 1988; MS277.000112; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Native Americans / Amicus, 1993 -- 1995; MS277.000113; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Lakota waste story, 1986 -- 1991; MS277.000114; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Pine Ridge vaccination program, 1987 -- 1991; MS277.000115; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry (ATSDR) report notes, 1988 -- 1991; MS277.000116; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Ballot initiatives, circa 1990 January -- 1990 November; MS277.000117; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Toxics - clippings, circa 1990 -- 1991; MS277.000118; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 9)
- California environment 1990 - 1991, MS277.000119; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Food / Water, 2008 -- 2011; MS277.000120; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Environment (general), circa 1990 -- 1991; MS277.000121; 1 Folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Weapons plant, circa 1988 -- 1991; MS277.000122; 1 Folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Weapons plants (Amicus), circa 1986 -- 1990; MS277.000123; 1 Folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Rocky flats, circa 1973 -- 1990; MS277.000124; 1 Folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Nuclear and other weapons, circa 1975 -- 1990; MS277.000125; 1 Folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Moscow trip, 1990 -- 1991; MS277.000126; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Moscow trip - travel guides, 1991; MS277.000127; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Electric vehicles story, 1991 January -- 1991 February; MS277.000128; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Rosebud Sioux, 1992 September 20; MS277.000129; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Native American issues, 1985 -- 2000; MS277.000130; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Eco-radicals / Pioneers / Organizations - EarthFirst!, Green Peace, etc., circa 1989 -- 2000; MS277.000131; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Japan (mostly environment), 1992 -- 1998; MS277.000132; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 7)
- EPA story II, 1989 February -- 1989 November; MS277.000133; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 8)
- EPA - Superfund, 1989 July -- 1989 October; MS277.000134; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 9)
- EPA / Congress etc. / OSHA, circa 1988 -- 1991; MS277.000135; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 10)
- "Toxic warriors", 1985 -- 1989; MS277.000136; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 11)
- States / Local environmental action, 1989 -- 1991; MS277.000137; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Industry and environmental groups, 1987 -- 1991; MS277.000138; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 13)
- EPA - North Carolina scandal, 1988 -- 1989; MS277.000139; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Recycling, circa 1988 -- 1991; MS277.000140; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Water treatment, circa 1988 -- 1990; MS277.000141; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Congress - Clinton years (environment), 1991 -- 2000; MS277.000142; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Jacksonville I, circa 1986; MS277.000143; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Jacksonville II, 1987 -- 1988; MS277.000144; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Jacksonville notes, 1986 -- 1988; MS277.000145; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Jacksonville Arkansas - clippings, 1992 -- 1998; MS277.000146; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Jacksonville III - Story, 1988 March 08 -- 1988 March 11; MS277.000147; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Jacksonville III - Notes - Interviews, 1987 -- 1988; MS277.000148; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Jacksonville documents, 1985 -- 1988; MS277.000149; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 8)
- American wilderness and land developments, circa 1987 -- 1991; MS277.000150; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Conservation Law Foundation (CLF) story and interviews, 1988 August 03 -- 1988 August 26; MS277.000151; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 1)
- New England emery and Conservation Law Foundation - clips, documents, 1983 -- 1988; MS277.000152; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Agriculture, 1988 -- 1990; MS277.000153; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 3)
- "Inside EPA" reports, 1989 March -- 1989 October; MS277.000154; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Agriculture / Pesticides 1990-1991, circa 1990 -- 1991; MS277.000155; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Global environmental issues, circa 1992 -- 2001; MS277.000156; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Air pollution, circa 1989 -- 1991; MS277.000157; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Global environment (and other countries), 1990 -- 1994; MS277.000158; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Medical waste - hospital management, 1996 -- 1999; MS277.000159; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 1)
- IV bags / Phthalates, 1997 -- 1999; MS277.000160; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Bay area - medical waste, 1996 -- 1999; MS277.000161; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Mercury, 1997 -- 1999; MS277.000162; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Medical waste disposal / Burning and companies, 1996 -- 1999; MS277.000163; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Polyvinyl chloride plastics (PVC) / Toys, etc., 1994 -- 1999; MS277.000164; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Dioxin / Diseases (general), 1993 -- 1999; MS277.000165; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Medical waste - contacts, interviews (general) and Detroit conference 1998, 1998 -- 1999; MS277.000166; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Health Care without Harm (general), 1997 -- 2000; MS277.000167; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Population, 1987 -- 1988; MS277.000168; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 10)
- International environment (dams, banks, etc.) Mark DuBois, 1986 -- 1987; MS277.000169; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Automobiles / Pollution, 1988 -- 1989; MS277.000170; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Forests (tropical rain) and reforestation, 1986 -- 1988; MS277.000171; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Randy Hays / Rain Forest Action Network, 1982 -- 1988; MS277.000172; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Ozone layer - my stories, notes, 1988 -- 1989; MS277.000173; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Lands use issues, 1992 -- 2000; MS277.000174; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Forests / rain, circa 1992 -- 2000; MS277.000175; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Tropical rainforests (Amazon etc.), 1993 -- 2000; MS277.000176; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Wildlife - endangered species, 1992 -- 2000; MS277.000177; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Animal rights / Tests on animals use toxics, 1993 -- 1998; MS277.000178; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Oil spills / Drilling, 1992 -- 2000; MS277.000179; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Water - pollution, supply, circa 1992 -- 2000; MS277.000180; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Rivers, dams, Everglades etc., 1993 -- 2000; MS277.000181; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Sewage treatment / Dumps, 1992 -- 2000; MS277.000182; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Population growth, 1993 -- 2000; MS277.000183; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Military (general) including non-lethal defense, 1992 -- 2000; MS277.000184; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Warfare threats (nuclear, bio, chemical), 1996 -- 2000; MS277.000185; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Nuclear power, 1992 -- 1994; MS277.000186; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Nuclear power (including Chernobyl), 1992 -- 2000; MS277.000187; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 14)
- United States Greens, deep ecology, native Americans, 1998 -- 1991; MS277.000188; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Garbage disposal, 1993 -- 2000; MS277.000189; 1 Folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Recycling, 1992 -- 1997; MS277.000190; 1 Folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Indoor pollution (lead, etc.), 1991 -- 2000; MS277.000191; 1 Folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 3)
- New England - general, 1988 -- 2000; MS277.000192; 1 Folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Toxics, circa 1986 -- 1991; MS277.000193; 1 Folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Oil spills / Drilling, circa 1989 -- 1991; MS277.000194; 1 Folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Trash disposal incineration, circa 1988 -- 1991; MS277.000195; 1 Folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Indoor pollution, circa 1988 -- 1991; MS277.000196; 1 Folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Military toxics, circa 1988 -- 1991; MS277.000197; 1 Folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Foreman bust / Earth First!, 1988 -- 1991; MS277.000198; 1 Folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Toxic waste, 1992 -- 1999; MS277.000199; 1 Folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Polluting corporations and EPA, 1992 -- 2000; MS277.000200; 1 Folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Waste not, 1992 -- 1997; MS277.000201; 1 Folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Hazardous waste news, circa 1992 -- 2000; MS277.000202; 1 Folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Hazardous waste 1993, 1993 -- 1994; MS277.000203; 1 Folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Food - pesticides, circa 1989 -- 1991; MS277.000204; 1 Folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Environmental groups, 1987 -- 1991; MS277.000205; 1 Folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Dioxin, 1992 -- 2000; MS277.000206; 1 Folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Agriculture issues, circa 1993 -- 2000; MS277.000207; 1 Folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Milk / Bovine Growth Hormone (BHG), 1991 -- 1999; MS277.000208; 1 Folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Biotechnology and agriculture food issues, circa 1993 -- 2000; MS277.000209; 1 Folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Biotechnology (general), circa 1993 -- 2001; MS277.000210; 1 Folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Cloning, 1993 -- 2000; MS277.000211; 1 Folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Gene watch / Gene exchange newsletter, 1996 -- 2000; MS277.000212; 1 Folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Pesticides - Dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane (DDT), etc., circa 1991 -- 2000; MS277.000213; 1 Folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Food - safety, irradiation, organic farming, circa 1992 -- 2000; MS277.000214; 1 Folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Mad cow disease, 1993 -- 2000; MS277.000215; 1 Folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Air pollution (general), circa 1992 -- 2000; MS277.000216; 1 Folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Acid rain, 1992 -- 2000; MS277.000217; 1 Folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 11)